Today we're going to make nice easy mint choc
chip ice cream using the ninja creami and if
you've never had one I'll very briefly talk
through the machine and how it [Music] works
So if you have followed this channel for a while
or if you haven't followed this channel for a
while and you don't subscribe then you'll not know
any of this but this channel is all about making
ice cream the most luxurious ice cream you're ever
going to eat and you make it at you can make it at
home in any ice cream machine going that really
is the only way to get super Luxury Ice Cream but
over the next year or so I'm going to show you
how to make ice cream without machines as well.
But this is a ninja creami they've been around for
a couple of years now uh they're super popular on
social media people turn really random stuff into
ice cream it it's got some serious downsides it
has some really good strong upsides too so just
quickly go through what this is it is a machine
that is essentially a blender it's a funny looking
blender the lid here has a blade in it that gets
spun around and you put a container in that has
a frozen ice cream base inside that blade cuts
through all that ice and makes those ice crystals
really tiny turns it into ice cream there is no
overrun on this at all it it just it it can't do
it it's not the right design it's not the right
machine for overrun overrun is the inclusion
of air what don't confuse a blender attachment
churning something up and increasing the size to
incorporating air it it's just folding some of
it in overrun in an ice cream machine or an ice
cream professional ice cream environment is when
small air bubbles are slowly incorporated into the
mix to increase the overall size that overrun that
air creates a much smoother texture better mouth
feel more luxurious ice scream okay but you can
get past that in the short term because this
is where this machine comes into its own this
machine is perfect if you just want to make ice
cream quickly eat it there and then and not not
stress about it is it perfect no but it is really
handy for people like that it's super cheap too I
mean really really cheap this is not a sponsored
video I'm not affiliated with Ninja at all had one
of these it broke told myself I probably wouldn't
get another one but get so many people ask me to
do ninja creamy videos here we are we are going to
make a quick base um for this we're going to make
a a condensed milk mint choc chip ice cream so for
this recipe you are going to need 300g of 2% milk,
300g of 33% whipping cream or thereabouts, and
300g of condensed milk 300g of condensed milk is
you know a kind of standard little can that you
buy in a supermarket that's kind of it it's so
easy let's just show you how to do it on the hob
first thing for this we're going to use natural
mint leaves to steep our base so I happen to have
some grinding my unit from my other business this
is Arc verie an arcv unit I'll put a link in
the description if you want to check it out so
with our peppermint leaves ready we're going to
start by adding our milk and our cream into the
pan and we want to just steep this mint in here so
we're going to take the leaves off the stalks and
and sit them in the dairy and warm up to about
50°C at that temperature the essential oils within
the actual mint themselves will start to leech
out into that liquid and give it a really nice
strong flavor we're going to leave it there for
about 30 minutes you don't have to have the heat
on for that entire time but it can help speed the
process up after that we're going to add in our
condens can of condensed milk in that goes this
is our sugars and our milk solids nonfat that's
what comes from using condensed milk so with all
those items combined we're going to leave it on
a hob no heat now for at least an hour if you can
do two then that would be an even stronger flavor
and after that's happened we're going to decant
that liquid into one of our containers here I
kind of want to strain out the mint leaves so I'm
going to do that here but I've got another spare
container I'm actually just going to add some
green food coloring to this one and pour that
remaining ice cream base into another container
we're going to put them both in the freezer
overnight so with our ice cream bases been in
the freezer overnight I'm going to split this
video into two I'm going to do the uncolored
mint ice cream and I'm going to take these
semi sweet guitar chocolate chips nice high
quality chocolate chips you don't need to use
high quality use whatever you like let's get
the uncolored mint ice cream out of freezer
so there's the colored one there's the uncolored
one I'm going to use this in another video because
I'm not going to make ice cream with it going to
make something else with it if you're interested
to know what that might be and you like Starbucks
like And subscribe so so if you unfamiliar there
is a line here that says fill Max fill so you pour
your base into that in the freezer it goes and to
prepare you simply drop that into there turn it
around till it locks into place you put our lid
on in the machine it goes once it sits
in turn it around until it locks into
place you heard that lock into place
now it is quite simply power
on ice cream it's going to get
[Music]
loud told you it was loud so now that that's
spun we need to press the lock button on the
side releases our container we're going to put
in some addins so to put addins in addins in in
you simply make a small divot in the center
all the way down the bottom like so [Music]
we're going to pour in some of our chocolate
chips pop that back into the container lid back
on but instead of the spin function we're going
to do the addin function which is here or mix in
[Music]
and un loock take that
out and a little Over the Top Shot I want
you to see how this turns out cuz a lot of
you said that you are unsure whether you
want to get these or not that is what the
result is okay texture-wise it's kind of
getting soft whoops it's kind of getting
soft so with that in mind we we need
to get some out here and get it into a
[Music] bowl couple of chocolate chips on top
two for me thumbnail a lot of ninja creamy
recipes a lot of ninja creamy recipes online
have such a low sugar that if you don't eat it
straight away you're going to have to reurn it
churn force a habit you're going to have
to respin it to make it any edible kind
of consistency I don't do that and I won't
do that I will make ninja creamy recipes
using really high quality ice cream recipes
so that if you put it back in the freezer
you can just eat it straight from the tub
without it being full of ice all right so a
quick there is our ice cream it
is nice and
smooth come on here we are nice and smooth
let's eat some shall [Music]
we nice and smooth texture no discernable
ice crystals no overrun like I said but you
don't always need that that's uh it's a different
playing field a ninja creamy versus a profession
profal machine different playing field don't
expect the same results you won't get them with
the ninja creamy you're going to get really
really good simple to make home ice cream it
lacks some of the finesse that a pro or Semi-Pro
machine will give you but not everybody needs that
for the for am money this costs what you know
like I said I think it was what 69 Canadian
on offer at Costco that's so cheap you can to
a degree forget all the all the downsides to
it really strong mint flavor don't bother cutting
up the actual leaves some people do that you know
for aesthetic reasons that's up to you when you
want to do that I don't like bits of chopped up
green in my ice cream but if you want to go for it
so this is the first video I'm going to show you
on the ninja creami really easy one to start
with it will get more complicated if you want
it to be I will also keep doing really easy simple
recipes for it as well cuz that's what it's for if
you love fudgy ice cream super decadent smooth
texture loads of different flavors make sure to
like and subscribe cuz this is all I do ice cream
I will all I also do like ice cream milk based
milkshakes and coffee drinks and stuff like that
and the other green ice cream base that I made
for this is going to be turned into a Starbucks
peppermint mocker frap so if that sounds good
and I promise you it is like And subscribe thanks
for much for watching and I will see you next week
[Music]